<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rachel&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rachel&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>this isn&#39;t your dad&#39;s job market</title>
      <link>/blog/this-isnt-your-dads-job-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 07:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/this-isnt-your-dads-job-market/</guid>
      <description>i&#39;ve title colors: behavioral  technical  practical  mental  title ## **#**  {#} --- today i start my new job. after a long 10-month job process and 400+ applications, i’ve finally accomplished what seemed like the (almost) impossible— going through this arduous process for candidates, practicing the technical questions, sending out regular applications, attending all the necessary networking events, and constantly tweaking my resume. writing out all those tasks on paper doesn’t really make it out to seem all that different from any other job search for any other person in the last 25 years of this millennium, but i know many are feeling and felt the way i do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build a Discord Bot 👾</title>
      <link>/blog/build-a-discord-bot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 21:22:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/build-a-discord-bot/</guid>
      <description>* this post is apart of a workshop i hosted for Starhacks 💫 *
Discord is a powerful messaging platform with great chat capabilities originally built to serve gaming communities. it has grown to a massive popularity and offers a lot of customization and autonomy via bots, custom moderation tools and more, which I’ll show you how to work with! in this tutorial I’ll show you how to set up a fully customizable Discord bot that can be running on your server in under 15 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huztle, a Gen-Z podcast</title>
      <link>/blog/huztle/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 07:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/huztle/</guid>
      <description>Huztle Art background after a number of setbacks and weeks of waiting, i have finally launched my (first?) podcast! Huztle is a “Gen-Z entrepreneurship podcast, where I interview up and coming GenZ innovators and founders in the field of STEM who have taken initiative to start their own businesses, and gain insight to their journey. They share their experiences, the lessons they’ve learned and their own visions for the future in their respective fields”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>whoami?</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 17:06:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>the blogger hi i&amp;rsquo;m Rachel! im a computer science student interested in web development, games and ar/vr.
right now i am currently studying at NYU, and this summer i will be interning @twitter. i made this blog to document some non-programming topics in my head. im not sure what else to say here so maybe ill update it more in the future :P
hey!  twitter - @therachelplan github - rachelombok email - rachel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
